with your tears, O women disciples,
the dazzling angels in the tomb
and to the murdering women.
Behold the tomb and understand,
for the Savior has risen from the grave.
is
The burbaring women coming with spices
To your great old Savior
Hear an angel say to them
Why do you love for the living with the dead
For as God he has risen from the dead
Voxa Patrikya, Eo, and Agio Pneumati, proxedum en ad.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Over unto the ages of ages of man,
By giving birth to the people of life,
We will be the kingdom of God,
From sin of virgin,
And will be the joy,
Instead of sorrow,
He who was appointed from you,
Who is both God and man,
That's kind of bad too
Alleluia, Alleluia, Alleluia, Alleluia, Alleluia, Alleluia, Alleluia, Alleluia, Alleluia,
Bye.
Again and again in peace, let us pray to the Lord.
and have mercy
and the love of us
with all the saints let us commend ourselves and one another and our whole life to Christ our God.
You are Lord.
Oti vrogeethe su t'o ono ma ki doksas t'e su i vasiilea tu patros ke tu eeuu ke tu agii pnevma tos,
neem ke aikeis tus aeo nas ton aeo no.
Ameen.
The thief's repentance plundered paradise, but the myrrh bearer's lament disclosed the joy that you had risen Christ God,
granting the world great mercy.
For those who dwell in the desert
The Lord may for God never ceases
For they are far from the world by me
Long Shabbat Rink
and in case
oh
having lifted me up to the mountains of your laws
Make me shine on the sky
with virtues that I may see your praise.
Glory to the Father and to the Son
and to the Holy Spirit, amen.
Both now and forever and to the ages of ages, amen.
In the Holy Spirit
is
made new and hastens back to its first condition for he is equal in strength to the father and the
word
Oh
is great fear,
for there when the thrones are placed
all the tribes and tongues
of the earth will be done.
Glory to the Father and to the Son
and to the Holy Spirit.
From now and forever
and to the ages of ages.
To the Holy Spirit
must be offered honor,
worship glory and might
as we fit our
For the Trinity is a unity in nature, but not in person.
I will be seated, Lord, and I will be seated.
Now shall I arise, says the Lord, now shall I be seated.
set him in safety and speak boldly in him.
The Lord's words are pure words, silver tried by fire, tested in earth, seven times refined.
Now shall I arise, says the Lord.
One shall set him in safety.
And speak boldly in peace.
Again and again in peace, let us pray to the Lord.
Help us, save us, have mercy upon us, and protect us, O God, by your grace.
Remembering our holy, immaculate, most blessed and glorious Lady, the Theotokos and ever-Virgin Mary,
with all the saints let us commend ourselves and one another
and our life to Christ our God.
For you are the King of Peace and the Savior of our souls.
And to you we offer up glory to the Father and to the Son and to the Holy Spirit,
now and ever and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
Let us praise as God of all power, the one who rose on the third day, smashed the gates of hell and roused the age-long dead from the grave,
who appeared to the murderers as it was his good pleasure to say to them
first of all. Rejoice,
and so revealing joy to the
apostles as a lone giver of life.
Therefore, with faith, the women
proclaim the tokens of victory
to the disciples. Hell groans,
death laments, the world
exalts, and all rejoice together.
For you, O Christ, have
granted resurrection to
all. Resurrection
to all.
On August 9th, we can
memory.
the holy apostle Matthias.
On this day, we also commemorate
the holy ten martyrs who contested
for the holy icon of our Savior Jesus Christ
at the brass gate.
Julian, Marcion, John, Jacob, Alexios,
Demetrios, Fotios, Peter, Leo, and Maria, the patrician.
On this day, we also commemorate
the contest of the holy martyr Antoninus.
Our devout Father, so is repose.
in prayer. On this day
we also commemorate the finding
of the venerable icon
of Kumulianon,
not made by hands. This event
was recorded by St. Gregory
Bishop of Nyssa.
By the intercessions
of your saints, O God, have mercy on us.
Amen.
Ασμωσής επεπτείας ραβδο, την εδικραμμύεται μετρουσραήλ πεζεύσοντη.
Είναι επιστρέφτηκος παραότης άρμασικο της ασύνοσεν.
Επεύρος διαγράψας το αήτη τον όπλοντι ο Χριστός ομέν.
Δόξα ο Ιμονότης
that looks us there.
As John abroad is accepted
as type and figure
of the great ministry,
by its body
gives the hearts
of the priests
from others,
while for the church
that has manned
and for steadfastness.
I have heard,
O my Lord and God,
your wise and divine
this
compensation's mystery.
Your great works I have
committed well, and your
God had praised with hands and
glorified.
O
tris macaris
don cilun
en no et
ati Christos o
Vasileus ce
Kyrius,
diu pepto
cerocius.
No en
silele astiste
on the proxies
When Jonas was wholly swallowed
Inside the belly of the sea monster
He stretched his hands out
And so clearly prefigured the saving passion of Christ
escaping from the
There on the third day he thus depicted the transcendent uprising of Christ our God,
who was fastened with nails on the cross in the flesh,
and by his third day of rising, enlightened and saved the world.
And with the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord, the Lord
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
We praise, we bless, and we worship the Lord.
You sin equal number to the Almighty.
Now bless the Maker, Father, and God.
Sing praises of the divine word that came now
transform the flaming fire into cooling dew and highly and highly exalt the eternal divine
Let us pray to the Lord.
our God, our holy, and you rest among the
holy ones, and to you we offer up glory
to the Father, and the Son,
and the Holy Spirit,
now and ever, and to the ages of
ages.
Amen.
Let every breath
praise the Lord.
Let us pray to the Lord our God that we may be made worthy to hear the Holy Gospel.
Lord have mercy.
Wisdom arise, let us hear the Holy Gospel.
Peace be with all of you.
And with your spirit.
The reading is from the Holy Gospel according to St. John.
Let us
be attentive that time Jesus revealed himself again to the disciples by the
sea of Tiberias and he revealed himself in this way Simon Peter Thomas called
the twin Nathaniel of Cana and Galilee the sons of Zebedee and the two others
of his disciples were together Simon Peter said to them I'm going fishing
they said to him we will go with you they went out and got into the boat but
But that night they caught nothing, just
this day was breaking, Jesus stood on the beach, but the disciples did not know that it was Jesus.
Jesus said to them, children, have you any fish? They answered him, no. He said to them, cast the
net on the right side of the boat and you will find some. So they cast it and now they were not
able to haul it in for the quantity of fish. The disciple whom Jesus loved said to Peter, it is the
Lord. When Simon Peter heard that it was the Lord, he put on his clothes for he was stripped for work
and sprang into the sea.
But the other disciples came in the boat
dragging the net full of fish, for they were not far from the land, but about a hundred yards off.
When they got out on land, they saw a charcoal fire.
Peter went aboard and hauled the net ashore full of large fish, a hundred and fifty-three of them.
And although there were so many, they knew it was the Lord.
Jesus came and took bread and gave it to them.
Now the third time that Jesus was revealed to the disciples, after he was raised from the dead.
Amen.
of Christ. For behold, through the cross joy has come to the whole world. Ever
blessing the Lord, let us praise his resurrection. For having endured the cross,
he destroyed death by death.
Wash me thoroughly from my weakness and cleanse me from my sins.
Against you alone have I sinned and done what is evil in your sight,
that you may be justified in your words
and prevent
when you are child.
For seeing you have love, truth,
you have shown me the hidden and secret
things of your wisdom.
You will make me hear of joy and gladness.
The bones which have been humbled will rejoice.
Create a clean heart.
Lord, pardon me, O God, and renew a right spirit within me.
Do not cast me out from your presence, and do not take your Holy Spirit from me.
Give me back the joy of your salvation, and establish me with your sovereign spirit.
O God, the God of my salvation,
deliver me from bloodshed,
and my tongue will rejoice at your justice.
For if you had wanted a sacrifice
I would have given it.
You will not take pleasure
from burnt offerings.
Do good to Zion, O Lord,
in your good pleasure
and let the walls of Jerusalem
so them be bebelts.
Then they will offer calves upon your altar
and have mercy on me, O God.
.
O Thou and forever, into the ages of ages, Amen.
At the prayers of the Mother of God, O merciful one,
blood of the multitude of my transgressions.
Ελεησόν με ο Θεός κατά το μεγαλεό σου και κατά το πλήθος των νύκτηρμών σου εξάλλειψον το ανώνυμά μου.
Αναστάσιο Ιησούς από το τάχο καθώς προείπτεν
Εύω και ειμην την αιώνια ζωή
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
προστασίες των τιμίων επουρανίων δυνάμεων ασωμάτων,
ηκεσίες του τιμίου ενδόξου προφήτου προδρόμου και βαπτίστου Ιωάννου,
των Αγίων ενδόξου και πανεφήμων αποστόλων, των Εναγής Πατέρων ημών,
μεγάλων ιεράρχων και οικουμενικών διδασκάλων,
Βασιλείου του Μεγάλου Γκρηγορείου, του Θεολόγου και Ιωάννου του Χρυσοστόμου,
Αθανασίου και Κύριε Λουιωάννου
του Ελέημον ως Πατριαρχών Αλεξανδρίας
Νικολάου του Εμμύρη Σπυρίδων ως Επισκόπου
Τριμιθούντος και Νεκτάριου
Πενταπόλεως των Θαυμάτουργών
των Αγίων ενδόξι Μεγάλου Μάρτυρων Γεωργίου
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Κύριε πάρκουσον ημών των αμαρτωλών δεωμένων σου και λέει σόν ημάς.
Κύριε αλάησον, κύριε αλάησον, κύριε αλάησον.
Κύριε αλάησον, κύριε αλάησον.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Συμβάχαμε.
Amen.
Thank you.
in
is
Μαρήν την άνθρωση, μαζί μόνοι σε η θάρια, θα καθέναν την κύρι,
και λιντά φορά, θα κουδηθούν όλα όλα, θα κουδηθούν οι θέοτος, και το δύο ημακτικό.
Αφήλε δεινάστας από θρόνων και ύψος εθαπινούς.
Την όντας ενέπλησεν αγαθόν και φουτούντας εξαφέρσιλε κενούς.
Την διμήρωτεραν τον Κερουθήν και εν λόξωτεραν ασύγκριτος τον Σεραφήν.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Amen.
and our truly Théodotos, you do be magnified.
προς γίνου ανεσάρτον σε μεγαλύνο με.
Έτυχε την ειρηνή του Κύριου Δέιθωμεν.
Κύριε Λέησο.
Help us, save us, have mercy on us and protect us, O God, by your grace.
Κύριε Παναγίας Αχράντου, υπερευλογημένης ενδόξου,
δεσπίνησημων Θεοτόκου και υπαρθένου Μαρίας.
Με τα πάντον των Αγίων νημών έψαντε σε αυτούς και αλληλούς και πάσαν την ζωή νημών.
Χριστό το Θεό παραθώμεθα.
Για όλοι οι πόρτες του Θεού θα σας ευχαριστώ.
Και για εσύ, θα σας ευχαριστώ.
Ευχαριστώ, για τον Βαλό, τον Ιωσό και τον Ιωσό.
Ωραία και πριν από όλες.
Αμέν.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
O He is the Lord our Lord.
Ipsut e kyrion don theon imon.
Che proskini de to ipopodio.
Don podon lab tu.
Don theonius eski.
Thomas the twin was fishing then
with Peter and Nathan.
and with the sons of Zebedee,
to others with them also.
While on the sea of Tiberias,
hearing the call from Christ God,
they cast nets on the boat's right side,
and they threw them up,
filled with so many fields.
Peter swam to Christ knowing it was him there.
And on this third, he often he showed them bread and fish on coals.
See, just fit, Demetrius.
An alternate night of hope.
Good.
The
Where are the belts that are fitting from?
There's a letter's more.
Go ahead and put them on your back.
Receive light the Father, and light the Spirit who guides with light all creation.
Oh
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Τον εντύσεις η ψήστης,
Τη πρέπει η γύρω στο Θεό.
Τον θεσκάστηκε.
Λέει σον ημάς ο Θεός,
κατά το μέρα λίγο
σχεδόντας ο πάρας
Κύριε Λέησου, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ειναι, ει
Τι δεώματα έβαλων των μακαρίων καμνείς του του θεωρών της Αγίας Οκλησίας Τάφης.
Επίσης, πάντων πράξε να με πατέρα και δεώσουμε τον Θεό.
Σας ευχαριστώ.
Κύριε Βασιλεύε Πουράνιε Θεέ Πάτερ Παντοκράτορ
Κύριε Ιε Μονόγενες Ιησού Χριστέ και Αγίον Πνεύμα
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Ο Θεός, Λέβαια, ο Θεός, ο Θεός, ο Θεός,
που θα δεξευτεί την πνευματική του κόσμου,
που θα δεξευτεί την πνευματική του κόσμου.
Προσταίξε την Τέη Συνήμων,
ο καθήμενος εκ δεξιών του Πατρός και ελεήσεων.
Ευχαριστώ. Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Και στη δόξα να αναπέμβομαι το Πατέριο και το Υιό,
και το Υιό Πνεύμα την Είναι και ο Υιός, όλοι σου μιλούν.
Ειρήνη, Πάση, τα σκεφαλά σιμών το Κύριο κλείνουμε.
Κύριε Άγιον Υψηλής κατοικών και δικατοινά εφορών
και το παντεφορείς αίμα του που βλέπουμε,
επί βάσης, εξήθιν την δημιουργία της πίστης του σωμάδου σου
και δεώμεθά σου.
Άγιοι, Αγίοι, Εξήν την χείριε σου, την αγάπη του,
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Κύριε Αιλήση, Κύριε Αιλήση, Κύριε Αιλήση, Κύριε Αιλήση, Κύριε Αιλήση, Κύριε Αιλήση, Κύριε Αιλήση, Κύριε Αιλήση, Κύριε Αιλήση, Κύριε Αιλήση, Κύριε Αιλήση, Κύριε Αιλήση, Κύριε Αιλήση, Κύριε Αιλήση, Κύριε Αιλήση, Κύριε Αιλήση, Κύριε Αιλήση, Κύριε Αιλήση, Κύριε Αιλήση, Κύριε Αιλήση, Κύριε Αιλήση, Κύριε Αιλήση, Κύρι
Σας ευχαριστώ πολύ.
Τον Αγίων και Θεόν του Πατώνα Αγίου και Άλλης,
Απόσταλ Μαθάις, Κάστατη Πατώνα, Κάστατη Νόπο, Εφθήμος,
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Φιλώξεν εψίστο και πηγήστε την εστροφή της Ανοκίας.
Φιλώριο και το Άρα Μεχάρης που σήμερα, Φιλώξεν εψίστο και πηγήστε την εστροφή της Ανοκίας.
Παρά την ονοελό σου, τη σκηνό σου σκύσε, Άγιος ο Θεός, Άγιος Ισχύρος, Άγιος Αθάνατος, ελέησον ημάς.
Ωραία.
God, holy, mighty, holy, mortal, have mercy on us.
Agios of theos, Agios sinceros, Agios at thanatos eleis onimas.
Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit.
All the immortal have mercy on us.
Agios Theos.
Agios Athanatus
Bene Ison Imas
Today has salvation come to us in the world
Let us sing to him who resurrected from the tomb
A Deus do céu
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Εν ειρηνή του Κύριου Δεϊθόμεν,
υπέρ της άνοθ ειρηνής και της σωτηρίας των ψυχών ημών του Κύριου Δεϊθόμεν,
υπέρ της ειρηνής του σύμπαντος κόσμου ασταθίας των Αγίων του Θεού Εκκλησίων
και της των πάντων ενός αιώσου του Κύριου Δεϊθόμεν.
Υπέρ του Αγίου Υκουτούτου και το μεταπίστεως ευλαβίας και φόβου Θεού Ισιόντων εν αυτό του Κύριου Δεϊθόμεν.
Υπέρ των ευσεβών και ορθοδόξων χριστιανών του Κύριου Δεϊθόμεν.
Κύριε Λέηστο
Υπέρ του Πατρός και Αρχιεπισκόπου Ήμων Μεθοδίου του Τιμίου
Presbyterian, the Son of Christ, the Son of God, the Son of God.
For our country, the President, and all those in public service, let us pray to the Lord.
for this city and for every city and land and for the faithful who live in them let us pray to the
Lord have mercy.
For favorable weather, for an abundance of the fruits of the earth,
and for peaceful times, let us pray to the Lord.
Lord have mercy.
For those who travel by land, sea, and air,
for the sick, the suffering, the captives, and for their salvation,
let us pray to the Lord.
Lord have mercy.
for our deliverance from Allah.
affliction, wrath, danger, and necessity,
let us pray to the Lord.
Help us, save us, have mercy on us,
and protect us, O God, by your grace.
Commemorating our most holy, pure, blessed,
and glorious Lady, the Theotokos,
and ever-Virgin Mary,
with all the saints, let us commend ourselves
in one another and our
whole life to Christ our God. Lord our God whose dominion is incomparable and
glory and comprehensible whose mercy is immeasurable and love for mankind
ineffable look upon us and upon this holy house in your loving kindness and
grant to us and to those who pray with us your abundant mercy and compassion. For
to you belong all glory honor and worship to the Father and to the Son and to the
Holy Spirit, now and forever
into the ages of ages.
Amen.
He who prepares mountains in his strength
through the intercessions of the Theodocus,
Savior, Savior.
The mountains shall greatly rejoice at the presence of the Lord, through the intercessions of the Theodos, Savior, save us.
God bless you, and God bless you.
Καίρι και αίκες του Θεού μας τον αιώνο νόμι
Τα σπρεσβεία στις Θεοτόκου
Σώτες όσον ημάς
Έττη και έττη εν ηρήνη του Κυρίου δε ηθόμεν
Κύριε αίσου
Αντιλαβούς όσον ελέησον και διαφύλαξον ημάς ο Θεός τη συγχάριτη
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Της Παναγίας Αχράντου υπερευλογημένης ενδόξου δεσπίνησημων Θεοτόκου και υπαρθένου Μαρίας.
Με τα πάντων των Αγίων ημωνεύσανε σε αυτούς και άλλοι τους και πάσαν την ζωή ημων.
Χριστό το Θεό παραθώμεθα.
Ο της όντο κράτος και σου εστίνει η βασιλεία και η δύναμης και η δόξα του Πατρός και του Υιου και του Αγίου Πνεύματος.
Μην και αεί και εις τους αίωνας των αιώνων.
The Lord loves the gates of Zion
More than all the dwellings of Jacob
Save us, O Son of God, who were transfigured on October, we sing to you, Alleluia.
Oh
O Thavar, met Amor, for this Salon, that's the Alleluia.
A man was saved, Mother Zion, and a man was born in earth.
Save us, O Son of God, who were transfigured on Mount Tabor.
we
Δόξα Πατρί και Υιο και Αγιο Πνεύμα Τι.
Και Λιγαίο Υιχαίς του Θεούνας των αιώνων, αμήν.
Ο μονογεννησιός και λόγος του Θεού, αθάνατος υπάρχον
και καταδεξάμενος θείατην, η μετέραν σωτηρίαν.
Σαρκωδίνε κι εις Αγίας Θεοτόκο
Υπάρχει η Παρδένω Μαρίας, ατρέπτωσεν ανθρωπή σας, σταυρωθήσε Χριστέ ο Θεός, καλά το θάνατο πάντη σας.
Ιησόν της Αγίας Τριάδος, συνδοξαζόμενος το Πατρί, εγώ Αγίου Πραγματί, σώσον ημών.
Again and again in peace, let us pray to the Lord.
Help us, save us, have mercy on us and protect us, O God, by your grace.
Commemorating our most holy, pure, blessed and glorious Lady, the Thailtokos and ever-Virgin Mary,
with all the saints, let us commend ourselves and one another in our whole life to Christ our God.
For you, O God, are good and love mankind,
and to you we offer glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit,
now and forever, and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
Συνήθεια.
το αγήνειον
πρεσβίες της θεωτώτου
ο το δωταθόξα αυσί
Σοφία ορθή
δεύτε προσκυνήσω μεν
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
και προσπάσουμεν Χριστό
σώσον ημάς η αίθερου
ο Αναστάσεις εκ νεκρών
ψαλονάς η αλληλούια
Amen.
is
I'm going to please remember this.
I'm going to see.
If we do this, we'll probably keep it on.
better and everything will stay on here a little better.
Does it have enough thing in it?
Can they empty or do they have stuff?
Thank you.
Yet es presvies deses, litrum eniecta na putas vicas imun.
O Lord, you were transfigured upon the mountain, and your disciples beheld your glory as far as they were able to bear it.
Oh, Christ.
are gone
so that when
they would see you being
crucified
they would know that
your passion was deliberate
and thus
go out to all
the world preaching
and proclaiming that you
are in truth the
Father's radio
Let us pray.
to the Lord.
For you are God,
our holy, and to you we offer
glory to the Father, and to the Son,
and to the Holy Spirit,
now and forever, and to the ages
of ages.
Amen.
Ae,
It's the truth.
I'm sorry.
Oh,
Άγιος ο Θεός, Άγιος ο Θεός, Άγιος ο Μάλλος της Ανέλης Μόνος,
Λόξα Πατρή και Υιού του, και ο Πνεύμα του Κενήν και Υιού της Ανέλης Μόνος.
Άγιος ο Θεός,
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Oh
Στον αιμόν, αμήν.
Δύναμη.
Ευχαριστούμενος ο ερθόμενος ο γνώματος Κύριου,
ευχαριστούμενος ιωτικών δόξης,
μασυαριστούμενος ο καθήμενος
και την προβλήματοί μου είναι και είναι και
Άγιος αγίος αθάνατος, αγίος αθάνατος, αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος αγίος
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Πρόσχομαι.
Καίνει το Κύριε το έλεος του εφημάες, καθαπέρε γυλτίσαμεν έπεισε.
Αγαλιάστε δίκαιοι εν Κυρίου, της ευθέσης πρέπει εν εσείς.
Σοφία.
Πρόσχομαι.
Θείους πρώτης επίστολης Παύλου το ανάγνωσμα
Πιώσουμε
Αδελφοί, ο Θεός οι μας τους Αποστόλους εσχά τους απέδειξεν,
ως επιθανατίους, ότι θέατρον εγενήθημεν το κόσμο,
και αγγέλις και ανθρώπις, εμείς μωροί δια Χριστών,
Είμαστε φρόνιμοι εν Χριστώ
Είμαστε νησί
Είστε ισχυροί, είμείς ενδόξοι, είμείς ατιμοι.
Άκρη της άρτη ώρας και πινόμεν και διψόμεν και γυμνητεύομεν και κολαφιζόμεντα
και αστατούμεν και κοπιόμεν εργαζόμενοι τες ιδίες κερσί.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Αυλογούμεν, διωκόμεν οι ανεθόμεθα, γλασφημούμεν οι παρακαλούμεν,
ως περί καθάρματα του κόσμου εγενήθημεν, πάντον περίψιμα έως άρθει.
που κεντρέπον ημάς γράφω ταύτα
αλλο στέκνα μου αγάπητα
εάν γαρμυρίους παιδαγωπαιδαγωγούς έχετε εν Χριστώ αλλούπολούς Πατέρας
εν γαρ Χριστό Ιησού διά του Ευαγελίου εγώ η μας γέννησα
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
We are in this time.
Wisdom.
The reading is from Paul's first letter to the Corinthians.
Let us be attentive.
Brethren, God has exhibited us apostles as last of all,
like men.
sentenced to death, because we have become a spectacle to the world, to angels and to men.
We are fools for Christ's sake, but you are wise in Christ. We are weak, but you are strong.
You are held in honor, but we in disrepute. To the present hour, we hunger and thirst. We are ill-clad
and buffeted and homeless, and we labor, working with our own hands. When reviled, we bless. When
persecuted we endure when slandered we try to conciliate we have become
and are now as the refuse of the world,
the off-scouring of all things.
I do not write this to make you ashamed,
but to admonish you as my beloved children.
For though you have countless guides in Christ,
you do not have many fathers.
For I became your father in Christ Jesus
through the gospel.
I urge you then, be imitators of me.
you
Σοφία ορθή ακούσομαι το Αγίου Ευαγγελίου, ηρήνη πάση
με το Πνεύμα της Σου.
με το κατά Μαθαίον Αγίου Ευαγγελίου το Ανάγνωσμα πρόσχομαι
Δόξα Σύ Κύριε, δόξα Σύ.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
με θυμόν, έως πότε ανέξω με ημών, φέρετε μη αυτόν ο δε, και επετίμησεν αυτό ο Ιησούς,
και εξήλθεν από αυτού το δαιμόνιο, και θεραπεύθει ο παής από τις ώρας εκείνης.
Τότε προσελθώντες οι μάθητε το Ιησού κατηδίαν, είπων, διατί ημίσου κι δινήθημεν, εκβάλειν αυτό.
Ο δε Ιησούς είπε αυτής
Δια την απιστίαν ημών
Αμήν
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
At that time a man came up to him and kneeling before him said,
Lord, have mercy on my son, for he is an epileptic and he suffers terribly,
for often he falls into the fire and often into the water.
And I brought him to your disciples and they could not heal him.
And Jesus answered, O faithless and perverse generation,
how long am I to be with you?
How long am I to bear with you? Bring him here to me.
And Jesus rebuked him, and the demon came out of him, and the boy was cured instantly.
Then the disciples came to Jesus privately and said, Why could we not cast it out?
He said to them, Because of your little faith.
For truly I say to you, if you have faith as a grain of mustard seed,
you will say to this mountain, Move hence to yonder place, and it will move,
and nothing will be impossible to you.
as they were gathering in Galilee, Jesus said,
said to them, The Son of Man is to be delivered into the hands of men, and they will kill him,
and he will be raised on the third day.
Please be seated.
Paracalo, Kathista.
Good morning, everybody.
This week, we celebrated the Feast of the Transfiguration of our Lord.
And even today, we're celebrating the after feast, if you will.
So when we have feasts, there's usually...
a fasting period of sorts, and yet we're already in the Dormition fast, so the Transfiguration
doesn't get its own special fast in the midst of that. And then the feast lasts about as long as
that fasting period, a week before to a week after. And so within the Feast of the Dormition,
we have this Feast of the Transfiguration, and we talked about it in the middle of the week,
so I won't belabor the point, but what happens, Christ goes up on my table,
he sits if you will at the peak
of the mountain. He brings three disciples with him. They fall asleep, right? They fall asleep.
In the Greek, I guess we have a funny way of playing with words and giving second and third
and fourth meanings to stuff. Kimithikan, right? Kimithikan. They went to pray with him, and yet
they fell asleep. Kimithikan, we have the word kimithiria, or the cemetery. We have the word
which means
means those who are not with it, aren't functioning at full capacity.
And then we have the word ex-hypnos, which means smart,
but it really means someone who is not asleep.
So the disciples, they're standing at the foot of the mountain.
They fall asleep.
Moses and Eliza show up.
God pretty much is ruling amongst the law and the prophets.
And as they're sleeping, his radiance is glowing.
they kind of come to
just about at the time when Moses and Elijah are about to leave.
Peter wakes up. He gets excited.
He says, Lord, let's build booths over here
so it stays this way forever so we can hang out here in the tents
and we can enjoy this just the way that it is.
And a cloud descends.
It covers over all of them.
Peter is fearful, puts his face on the ground and cries
because he realizes that he's talking in a very...
familiar way to the person who is God himself. It's hard sometimes to hold two dynamics within
a relationship intention. And so the voice says, this is my beloved son and whom I'm pleased.
Hear him, listen to him. And so Jesus walks over to Peter, touches him and he says, get up. It's
okay. Don't be afraid. And this is a strange dynamic, but immediately following this reading,
we have today's gospel.
reading. We have Jesus and the three descending down the mountain, if you will, entering into
the valley, entering into, you know, your normal, into your normal territory. And an old man comes
running to him, falls at his knees and is begging him, Lord, heal my son. Heal my son because I
brought him to your disciples and they couldn't do anything about it. But since he was a young
child
and this always jumps out at me it started doing so earlier since he was a young child not since
he was a baby not from birth but since he was a young child meaning the kid has had some life
experience before this thing starts happening since he was a young child he's been falling
into fire and into water pretty much he's an epileptic he's convulsing and he falls down
dangerous
He might knock over a candle lamp and catch himself on fire.
He might be walking by the river and collapse into the water and drown.
He loses his senses and faces imminent danger.
Can you heal him because I brought him to your disciples and they couldn't do anything about it?
And Jesus says, in what sounds harsh in our tone,
O faithless and perverse generation
how long am I to be with you?
How long am I to bear with you?
This is strange.
It doesn't line up with how we think of Jesus,
compassionate and loving and merciful and gentle and kind.
And this man, he's just meeting right now.
Why is he lashing out at him?
Having essentially come down from the mountain,
and he sees what?
He sees faithlessness.
mess. Not a lack of understanding who God is.
and accepting that God is real,
but a disconnect between that understanding
and a change in his life
to make it be real in his everyday dynamic.
Who thinks God is real?
Who thinks God has a son whose name is Jesus?
Who thinks that son is also God?
These are things that we believe,
which is one part of faith.
but
If we believe these things, then our life changes.
We can't just go about worshiping LeBron James.
We can't go about idolizing Tom Brady.
We can't go about hoping that our countries or that our governments
are going to find a way to heal the world and to transform it.
Because none of those idols or heroes or whatever you have it are God.
And therefore, they don't have the capacity to do that.
So when we put our hope in these other things,
in these other people, in these different dynamics,
what happens is we find ourselves kneeling down in front of them,
trying to become like them,
because we think this is the path to a better life for me.
If I can become a pro basketball player,
if I can become a pro baseball player,
if I can play sports
if I can become a politician
if I can be anything that separates me
if I can be an influencer
if I can be on the internet to make money really easy
while sitting in a chair
it doesn't matter what we pick
but when we distort who God is
and what he's calling us to do and to be
and we put it aside
for what the world is showing.
us is the way to be for success, then things fall apart. And so when he's telling this man,
oh, faithless and perverse generation, he's not talking just to him. He's talking to the
generation, which is not just the people that have been around for the last 20 years, although
that word also lasts and works.
Llenos is not just a tribe of people.
It's both the people of this time.
It's both the people of a genealogy of.
And it doesn't necessarily mean blood-related.
It means ethnic culture, if you will.
And so in talking to this man, he's talking to Israel itself.
Because the last time somebody came down from a mountain,
having interacted with God and found himself among the Jewish people,
they had taken all of their gold
and made a golden calf, and started worshiping that.
And so on the transfiguration, as Christ comes down the mountain,
and his disciples aren't able to do what even they are surprised about.
They cannot heal this man's son.
Christ resets the dynamic for them.
And he has that outburst, because he's talking to his people, all of them.
If he was here today, he would be
talking to us and calling
us faithless.
Not because we don't
think he's real,
but because we
don't live as if he is.
There's a gap there
between the two.
When we're
baptized, when we're married
in the church,
that's the
beginning of life in Christ. That's the beginning of a marriage. The relationship, however, just
because it's begotten its seal, if you will, of approval and officiality, it doesn't last on its
own just magically. It doesn't work if nobody puts effort in. It doesn't work if the two aren't coming
together and communicating.
If the two aren't bearing one another
burdens, if the two aren't going
about inquiring about each other's
well-being.
Marriage is
a life in Christ.
One's faithfulness
is a life
in Christ.
Every day
God gives us the ability to breathe
in.
Κάθε μέρα
μας δίνει τη δυνατότητα
να αναπνεύσουμε
Then...
to take a deep breath in,
but that word for breath in the Greek
is the same word for spirit.
Every day he gives us the potential
to breathe in
and to be inspired by his Holy Spirit.
Because his Holy Spirit
goes where it wants,
but it's our bodies
that are meant to be temples for it.
and so when this young man is brought
forward because there's something wrong,
Christ's
response is,
bring him here
to me.
When there's something
wrong in our lives,
the response is,
bring it here
to him.
That can be a conversation.
that can
be a confession. That can be communion. That can be a blessing of your marriage. That can
be a baptism or a chrismation. But the response is, bring what you have to me. Let me not
get in the way of that right and so he rebukes
and the demon comes out of him
and the boy is cured instantly.
And the disciples say,
why doesn't it work?
And he says, because of your little faith.
Not because you don't know that I'm God.
Peter, James, and John
just saw him on the mountain.
His clothes changed color.
They didn't recognize him at first.
Moses and Elijah were there with him.
They know that this is not
your regular human being.
No
nor is it your run-of-the-mill prophet.
And yet there's dissonance.
It doesn't register.
They don't really understand
ina komaligo ki mizmen.
And yet, they come too.
And they're happy about noticing what's happening,
and they want to be there.
They want to be here.
They want to be worshiping God and receiving communion,
and to be able to be here.
indefinitely, which most of us were not even there yet, but they've gotten to that point.
And Christ says to them, no, that's not what's going to happen. We have to go back into the world
because the son of man will be crucified, put to death, and on the third day he will rise.
It's nice to be here joyfully celebrating and coming into contact and praying to our wonderful
and merciful God, and yet
He
himself says we don't get to stay here. We go back into the world where we will be grabbed,
where we will be tortured, where life will be difficult, where life will be challenging,
where we will be spat upon, we will be ridiculed, we will be whipped,
we will be put on a cross. We will have to carry that cross there to begin with,
and then we're going to die.
and after we die,
we will rise again.
And this is the message that he's trying to get through to them,
that life isn't meant to be always pleasant.
That when we have moments where it is,
we are to appreciate it.
We are to take it all in.
We are to be encouraged by it.
We are to be sustained by it.
And we're not supposed to
supposed to be left back there in our mind. We are supposed to come back into ourselves,
where we wake up, where we get smart, where we go back into the world,
and we show the world the way back to God, who made the world. When Moses saw what he saw down
in the valley he broke the idol and God said to him
Moses, look, let me wipe them all out.
Let me get rid of all of them.
They're not any good.
And I'll grab some rocks and I'll turn them into people
and we'll start fresh from you and your family.
And Moses said, no, Lord, you're patient.
You're gentle.
You're kind.
You're merciful.
Give us another chance.
We know who you are.
Let us show you who we are.
And so...
So Moses goes back up the mountain for 40 more days.
And then he receives the commandments all over again
and he brings them down.
And this time the people, they're not busy with a cow.
They're waiting to receive him because they've learned the lesson.
This is a little bit of today's dynamic.
Christ comes down.
Christ meets us.
Christ is wondering why aren't we going
για τον.
Γιατί δεν αρχινάμε απ' την αρχή.
Γιατί δεν τον έχουμε σαν τον σωστό προορισμό μας.
Και γιατί όταν ανεβαίνουμε εδώ στο όρος και τον δοξάζουμε
με το που ξανακατεβαίνουμε
τον ξεχνάμε.
and our life is not like it was before.
For an hour and a half to two hours,
we're here prayerfully
and our mind wanders.
For six and a half to seven days,
we're out there
with our mind wandering
and sometimes our bodies wandering.
Are we praying through that process?
Are we collecting ourselves?
Are we remembering ourselves?
Are we finding our spirit and our body and making them one
so that we can bring it here again to Him
so that it can be renewed and go out into the world and healed?
Because if we have faith the size of a mustard seed,
we can tell the mountain over there to move and it will move.
But faith means doing the things, not just thinking.
them, which means faith
is hard work.
Faith is hard work.
God bless and keep you. Please rise so that we
can continue worshiping and
praising our merciful God.
Again
in countless times we fall down
before you and we implore you, O good one,
who
loves mankind, that you having regarded
our prayer may cleanse our souls and bodies
from every defilement of flesh and spirit
and grant to us to stand
before your holy altar of sacrifice,
free of
guilt and condemnation. Grant also God to those who pray with us progress in life, faith
and spiritual understanding. Grant that they always worship you with awe and love, partake
of your holy mysteries without guilt or condemnation, and be deemed worthy of your celestial kingdom.
That ever guarded by your mind we may ascribe glory to you, to the Father, and to the Son,
and to the Holy Spirit, now and forever and to the ages of ages.
Amen.
No one bound by carnal desires and pleasures.
is worthy to approach, draw near, minister to you, the King of glory.
For to serve you is great and awesome even for the heavenly powers.
And yet because of your ineffable and immeasurable love for mankind, you impassively and immutably
became man.
You as the master of all became our high priest and delivered unto us the sacred service of
this liturgical sacrifice without the shedding of blood.
Indeed, Lord our God, you alone reign over the celestial and the terrestrial.
you
aloft on the cherubic throne lord of the seraphim and king of israel the only holy and resting among
the holy ones i now beseech you who alone are good and inclined to hear look down upon me your sinful
and unprofitable servant
and cleanse my soul and heart of a wicked conscience and enable me by the power of your
holy spirit clothed with the grace of the priesthood to stand before your holy table and celebrate the
the mystery of Your holy and clear body.
your precious blood I come before you with my head bowed and I implore you turn
not your face away from me nor reject me from among your children but make me
your sinful and unworthy servant worthy to offer these gifts to you for you were
the one who both offers and is offered the one who was received and is
distributed O Christ our God and to you we offer glory with your father who is
without beginning your all-holy good and life creating spirit now and forever
into the ages of ages.
Amen.
Υπονίζω μες και της οδοποιώ τριά δίκτω τρισάγιον ήμρουσάζοντες.
Βάσαν ήμπιωτική να ποθώμεθα με έρημναν ως τον βασιλέα τον όλο με το εξώμενοι.
Σ' αγγελικές αοράθους περιφερόμουν αντάξεσαιν αλληλούια, αλληλούια, αλληλούια.
Субтитры создавал DimaTorzok
Thank you.
Oh
I
Be only.
The
Oh
Πάντον ημών εις Θεί Κύριος ο Θεός,
εν τη βασιλιά αυτού πάντοτε.
Μιν και αίγε
Κεστου σε ονάστο με ονό
May the Lord our God
remember all of us in this kingdom
both now and forever
and to the ages
of ages
Amen.
Thank you.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh
I'm sorry.
Oh
oh
Υπέρ του Άγιου οικοτού του και το μεταπίστεως ευλαβδίας και φόβου Θεού
Υσιόντω μεν αυτό του Κύριου δεηθώμε
Υπέρ του Ιστή Νέη μας από πάσης τρίψεως όργης
Κίνδυνο και ανάγκης του Κύριου δεηθώμε
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
That the whole day may be perfect, only peaceful and sinless, let us ask the Lord.
for an
Angel of peace, a faithful guide, a guardian of our souls and bodies, let us ask the Lord.
For pardon and remission of our sins and transgressions, let us ask the Lord.
For that which is good and beneficial for our souls and for peace for the world, let us ask the Lord.
that we may complete
our many times of our life
in peace and repentance.
Let us ask the Lord.
And let us ask for a Christian
into our life,
peaceful,
without shame and suffering,
and for a good defense
before the awesome judgment seat of Christ.
Commemorating our most holy, pure, blessed and glorious Lady,
the Felt Ocos and Ever-Virgin Mary, with all the saints,
let us commend ourselves and one another and our whole life to Christ our God.
Lord God Almighty, you alone are holy.
You accept the sacrifice of praise from those who call upon you with their whole heart,
even
Αντρίζεσαι από τους πνεύτες, και έδωσε το πνεύτερος και το πνεύτερος του σύντου.
Υπάρχει να δώσεις δικαιώσεις και δικαιώσεις σπίτου για τα πνεύτερα μας και τα φαίντερα του ανθρώπους.
Θεωρούμε να βρει ευκαιρία στη δύο σας, ώστε να δώσεις ευκαιρία στη δύο σας,
ώστε να δώσεις ευκαιρία στη δύο σας, ώστε να δώσεις ευκαιρία στη δύο σας,
και ζωπιώς σου πνεύματι
Peace be with all of you.
Let us love one another that with oneness of mind we may confess.
I bless you.
Holy Spirit, Trinity, one in essence and undivided.
The doors, the doors in wisdom, let us be attentive.
I believe in one God, Father Almighty, creator of heaven and earth and of all things visible and invisible,
and in one Lord Jesus Christ, the only begotten Son of God.
God, begotten of the Father before all ages, light of light, true God of true God, begotten,
not created, of one essence with the Father through whom all things were made, who for
us men and for our salvation came down from heaven and was incarnate of the Holy Spirit
and the Virgin Mary and became man.
He was crucified for us under Pontius Pilate and suffered and was buried, and he rose on
the third day according to the scriptures.
he ascended into heaven and is seated at the right hand of the Father
and he will
come again with glory to judge the living and the dead his kingdom shall have no end and in the holy
spirit the lord the creator of life who proceeds from the father who together with the father and
the son is worshiped and glorified who spoke through the prophets in one holy catholic and
apostolic church i confess one baptism for the forgiveness of sins i look for the resurrection
of the dead and the life of the age to come amen let us stand alive let us stand in awe let us be
attentive
που μπορούμε να δημιουργήσουμε μόνο το πόδιο.
Η χάρη του Κύριου ημών Ιησού Χριστού και η αγάπη του Θεού και Πατρός
και η κοινωνία του Αγίου Πνεύματος, η μεταπάντων ημών.
Αν τους χωμένους καρδίους
Let us give thanks to the Lord.
It is proper and right to him, you to bless you, to praise you, to give thanks to you, and to worship you in every place of your dominion.
For you, O God, are ineffable, inconceivable, invisible, incomprehensible, existing forever, forever the same, you and your only begotten Son and your Holy Spirit.
You brought us out of nothing into being, and when we had fallen away, you raised us up again.
You left nothing undone until you had led us up to heaven and granted us your kingdom, which is to come.
For all these things we thank you and your only begotten Son and your Holy Spirit for all things we know and do not know,
for blessings manifest and hidden that have been bestowed on us.
We thank you also for this liturgy which you have deigned to receive from our hands,
even though thousands of archangels and heads of thousands of angels stand around you,
the cherubim and seraphim, six-wing, many-eyed, soaring aloft upon their rings,
singing the triumphal hymn, exclaiming, proclaiming, and saying,
The Lord is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is the one who is
Together with his blessed powers, Master, who loves mankind,
we also exclaim and say, Holy are you, and most holy you, and your only begotten Son,
and your Holy Spirit. Holy are you, and most holy and sublime is your glory.
You select your word that you gave your only begotten Son,
so that everyone who believes in him should not perish, but have eternal life.
When he had come and fulfilled for our sake the entire plan of salvation,
on the night in which he was delivered up, or rather, when he had delivered himself up to the life of the word,
He took bread in his holy pure emblems hands.
Σε ευχαριστώ και ευχαριστώ που έφερε και έφερε το σύνοδιο του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι του σύντοι
Isafes in Amartion
Take it, this is my body
Which is broken for you
For the remission of sins
Piatek saftu pandes
Tutto estito emma munto
Tis kenis diafikis
To iperimon ke polon ekhinomenon
Isafes in Amartion
Drink of this, all of you
This is my blood of the new covenant
Which is shed for you
information
for the remission of sins.
Amen.
For the same universe,
we went for the cross,
the tomb of resurrection
on the third day,
the ascension to heaven,
the earth,
and the second glory
is coming again.
Thus I,
don't show sin prosper,
O man,
kata panda,
ke via panda,
your own love,
your own,
we offer to you
and all
and for all.
Once again we offer to you this spiritual worship without the shedding of blood.
And we beseech and pray and entreat you.
Send down your Holy Spirit upon us and upon the gifts you are presented.
Ευλόγησον δέσποδα των Άγιων Άρθων και ποιήσον των μενάρθων τούτων τίμιων σώμα του Χριστού σου. Αμήν.
Ευλόγησον δέσποδα των Άγιων Ποτήριων, το δέντο ποτήριο του τούτων τίμιων αίμα του Χριστού σου. Αμήν.
ευλόγησοντας που τα αμφότερα τα Άγια
Metavallon to Plevmatisu to Agio.
Amen. Amen. Amen.
So that they may be for those who partake of them
for vigilance of soul, remission of sins,
communion of your Holy Spirit,
fullness of the kingdom of heaven,
boldness before you, not for judgment or condemnation.
Again, we offer you the spiritual worship
for those who have reposed in the faith,
forefathers, fathers, patriarchs, prophets,
apostles, preachers, evangelists, martyrs,
confessors, ascetics, and for every righteous spirit
made perfect in faith.
Ex-Arae Tos, the Pana Giais
Αχράνου οι υπερευλογημένοι σεν δόξου δεσπίνης σήμων, Θεοτόκου και υπαρφένου, Μαρία.
Amen.
and in peace, Lord, so that in their turn,
we may live common, serenity, and all piety, and virtue.
Great is the name of the Holy Trinity,
now and forever, through the ages of ages.
Remember, Lord, this city in which we live,
and every city and land of the faithful who live in them.
Remember, Lord, those who travel by land,
seeing near the sick and suffering,
the captives for salvation.
Remember those who bear fruit,
and the works of the holy trekkers,
and those who are mindful of the poor,
and upon us all, since forth and mercy.
Thank you.
among the first remember Lord Archbishop and father method the Ostrans
into your holy churches and peace safety honor and health on the length of
day journey teaching the word of your truth and remember those whom each one
of us has in mind and all the people and granted with one voice and one heart we
may glorify and praise your most honorable
majestic name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit now and forever
into the ages of ages having commemorated all the Saints again and
again in peace let us pray to the Lord for the precious gifts here presented
and consecrated, let us pray to the Lord.
Όπως ο φιλάνθρωπος Θεός ή μόνο προσδεξάμενος αυτά εις το Άγιο και υπερ Ουράνιον και Νοερόν αυτού θυσιαστήριον, ίσως μην ευωδίας πνευματικής αντικαταπέμψη, μην την Θεία Χάρη και την δωρεάν του Αγίου Πνεύματος δε ηθόμεν.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Master, with boldness and without condemnation,
to dare call you the heavenly Godfather, and to say...
Our Father, who art in heaven, hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come, thy will be done on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread, and forgive us our trespasses
as we forgive those who trespass against us.
And lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil.
Father, my dear, O'endis Uranis,
Agia, speak to the name of your name.
Come to your kingdom,
speak to your name.
Όσον ουρανό και πληθυσκής, τον άρθο τον ημών, τον ευριούσιο τρόση της σύνειρων.
Είμαι σύνει φτύγει, ειμών.
Και μίσεν έγισι μας εις πειρασμόν, αλλά δείσαι εμάς από τον πονηρού.
Ότι σου έστειλει η Βασιλεία και η δύναμης και η δόξα του Πατρός και του Υιού και του Άγιου Πνεύματος,
νυμ και αϊκέ εις τους αιώνας των αιών ολών.
Αμήν.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Συν Κύριε
Ο Θεός η λάστη μην τον αμαρτωλώ και λέει
«Πρόσχομαι τα Αγία Της, Αγίες τα Χωριστή, για τους άνθρωποι που έρθουν»
Μελίζεται και διαμερίζεται ο Ανός του Θεού, ο μελιζόμενος και μη διαρρούμενος
ο πάντα πιστιωμένος και μη δέπεται δεπανωμένος, αλλά τους μεταίχοντες αγιάζουν
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
thank you
we give thanks to you invisible king who by your boundless power fashion the universe and
in the multitude of your mercy brought all things from nothing into being look up down
from heaven o master upon those who have bowed their heads before you for they have not bowed
before flesh and blood but before you be awesome god therefore our master makes smooth and beneficial
for us all whatever lies ahead according to the need of each day with those who say travel
Welcome to the Sikers of our Chosen Bothers.
Harking the Lord.
lord jesus christ our god from your holy dwelling place and from the throne of glory of your
kingdom and come to sanctify us you who are enthroned with the father on high
and are present among us invisibly here and with your mighty hand grant communion of your
most pure body and your precious blood to us and to go through us to all the people
i believe and confess oh lord that you are truly the christ the son of the living god who came
into the world to save sinners of whom i am the first i also believe that this is truly your pure
body and this is truly your precious blood therefore i pray to you have mercy upon me
and forgive my transgressions.
I am a Christian.
spirit and honestly nourishes the mind you have smitten me with your earning oh christ
my your divine arrows you have changed me that burn up with spiritual fire my sins and
grant me to be filled with delight in you so that weeping for joy of the magnifier
since it is not a wedding garment and being bound up i shall be cast out by the angels
cleanse oh lord the fruit of my soul and savior as you're the one who loves my kind
Αλλά εις κάταξη και εις διασμόν ψυχήστικες σωμάτους και εις αραβόνω της μελούς της ζωής του Βασιλείας.
Εμίδετε προσκαλέστε τον Θεό αγαθόν έστει, τίθεσε τον Κυρίο την αρχόδο της σωτηρίας μου.
Του δίπλου σου τιμιστή του σήμερου, Ιε Θεού κοινωνάμε παράλλακο, μεταξευθύρισου το μυστήριο του φίλου μας,
σου δώσω καταπόλοιο δασύ, άλλο σου στις ολυστής ογωγός σου, μισθήμη Κύριο την Βσιλεία σου.
Αλληλούια!
Ευχαριστώ, ευχαριστώ.
και Πανάγιον, σώμα του Κυρίου και Θεοίη της ο Τύριος ημώνης του Χριστού,
εις άφηση μου, αμαρτιών και ζωή νέων, η ανομία.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Lord, we are in the name of Jesus Christ.
We wish my sins and my sins.
Let's just touch my lips.
Let's just roll my negrity.
I'm going to find it in my sins.
Having beheld the resurrection of Christ,
I believe, Lord Jesus,
the only
when you cross your cross.
We celebrate.
We rise to your Christ and glory
for you, our God,
and our King, we know no one.
Amen.
I'm just a little bit
Is that
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh
Oh, oh, oh, oh.
Praise the Lord
From the heaven
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh
That sounds so good. I feel bad interrupting.
As we come forward to receive Holy Communion,
please allow for the chanters to come forward and receive
so they can return to their spots,
and then allow for families with infants and young children
to come forward first.
I don't know how aware we are of this as a community,
but when we do see lit candles with babies approaching,
it's probably because they've been very recently baptized,
and so they're receiving communion for one of the first few times
they're in the church
So usually if you see somebody with a lit candle in liturgy, they then cut to the front of the line also.
God bless you all.
Metaphobo Theupis, Theus chea dapis, prosentete with the fear of God, with faith and with love, draw near.
Amen, amen, amen. Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord.
The Lord is God and has a peace.
I love you.
Κατρίνα.
εις άφεσιν αμαρτιών και στη ζωή αιώνιων. Αμήν.
Μεταλαμβάνει ο δούλος του Θεού, σώμα και αίμα Χριστού,
Μεταλαμβάνει η δούλη του Θεού Ελένη, σώμα και αίμα Χριστού,
εις άφεσιν αμαρτιών και στη ζωή αιώνιων. Αμήν.
Μεταλαμβάνει η δούλη του Θεού, στυλιανή, σώμα και αίμα Χριστού,
Μεταλαμβάνει η δούλη του Θεού Λάζαρου Σώμα και με Χριστού
Εισάφεσιν αμαρτιών εις τη ζωή αιώνιων. Αμήν.
Μεταλαμβάνει η δούλη του Θεού Μαρίνα Πρεσβυτέρα Σώμα και με Χριστού
Μεταλαμβάνει η δούλη του Θεού Ισού Λάζαρου Σώμα και με Χριστού
για την αποδελθήση των συνθήκων και της ζωής.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
and
the
Amen.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Κι αίμα Χριστού, μας άφησε να μαρτιώνει και στη ζωή του αιώνα. Αμήν.
Μεταλαμβάνει ο δούλος του Θεού Μαρία, τη σώμα.
Μεταλαμβάνει ο δούλος του Θεού, το σώμα και το λόγο του Θεού,
για την αιώνα της σύνσης και τη ζωή του αιώνα.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
came up
the servant of god
in life eternal amen the servant of god who sees the body and the lord of christ for their
mission sins in life eternal amen the servant of god
the body which is the body
the Lord of Christ
for the mission of sins
and life
Amen.
A servant of God who exes us the body and blood of Christ who then has his sins in life eternal.
and the Lord is the Holy Spirit.
The Holy Spirit is the Holy Spirit.
Με θελαμβάνει ο δούλος του Θεού Μαρτίων και Σύμμα και Αίμα Χριστού.
Είς άφησε ο Μαρτίων και στη ζωή μου.
The servant of God, Ιωάννα, who sees the body and the bride of Christ,
with her omission of sins and life eternal.
Με θελαμβάνει ο δούλος του Θεού Αλέξανδρου, Σύμμα και Αίμα Χριστού.
Με σάφερση με το Μαρτιόν και στον κοινό.
Zohar, amen, amen, a servant of God, a man who listens to the body, and the Lord of Christ, for the remission of sins, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life, and life,
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
μεταλαμβάνει ο δούλος του Θεού και ο αγίος
σώμα και αίμα Χριστού
εις άφεσαι να ματιών και στη ζωή
να μην μεταλαμβάνει ο δούλος του Θεού
και στη ζωή αιώνια να μην
μεταλαμβάνει ο δούλος του Θεού Θεόδωρος
Σώμα και με Χριστώ Ισα.
Σε αμαρτιών και στη ζωή αιώνιων. Αμήν.
has saved us
be exalted oh God above the heavens
and let your glory be over all the earth
blessed is our God
now and forever into the ages of ages
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Χαίρον Σύνην Τσού, Αλληλούια, Αλληλούια, Αλληλούια.
Πορθεί μεταλλαβώντες των Θείων Άγιων, αχράντων, αθανάτων, επουρανίων και ζωποιών φρικτών του Χριστού Μυστηρίων,
αξίως ευχαριστήσωμεν τον Κύριο.
Κύριε Λέησέο.
Ωραία, χρειάζοντας, χρειάζοντας, χρειάζοντας, χρειάζοντας, χρειάζοντας, χρειάζοντας, χρειάζοντας, χρειάζοντας, χρειάζοντας, χρειάζοντας, χρειάζοντας, χρειάζοντας, χρειάζοντας, χρειάζοντας, χρειάζοντας, χρειάζοντας, χρειάζοντας, χρειάζοντας, χρειάζοντας, χρειάζοντας, χρειάζοντας, χρειάζοντας, χρειάζοντας, χρειάζοντας, χρ
Τιν ημέρα πάσαν τελείαν, Άγιοι, Ανερηνικοί και Αναμάρθητον, ατισάμενοι, αυτούς και αλλήλους και πάσαν την ζωήν ημών. Χριστό του Θεού παραθώμεθα.
For you, our sanctification, and to you we give glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit, now and forever, into the ages of ages.
Let us go forth in peace, let us pray to the Lord.
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Σας ευχαριστώ.
we give thanks to you
Christ our God for you
for the Lord and the promise of the Lord
and the promise of the Lord
Oh.
Από τον ίδιο Θεές του αιώνα
Αμήν
Προστασίες των Τιμίων Ουρανίων Δυνάμεων Ασωμάτων
Ικησίες του Τιμίου Εντόξου, Προφήτου Παδρορόμου και Βαπτιστού Ιωάννου
Τον Αγίων Εντόξου Πανευθύμων Αποστόλων
Τον Αγίων Εντόξου Παλήγων Ακήδων
Τον Οσίων και Θεοφόρων Πατέρα Ιμών
Τον Αγίος Παντρός Ιωάννου
Αργιεπισκόπι του Ξενοπόλαιου Σεπιζοστόμου
Υπότιτλοι AUTHORWAVE
Have mercy on us and save us, for he is good and loves mankind.
I bless you all.
Please be seated for just a moment.
Where is she?
Ah, there she is.
Anna.
And I see that they're here in the back.
I wasn't sure if they were here earlier.
here. So first and foremost,
most, as I say every
week because I'm still getting used to it, we don't
pass a tray in the church, but we do
put it in the corner there for everybody on their way
out and up to coffee hour
to be able to put
their generous offering
on their way out.
Next to that is also a little announcement about
our great Vespers this week, and
if we're able to help in any
way, shape, or form.
What if I start?
Come on.
hello
yes the announcement the the can you can you put it back up there and give me okay
louder megan
I just wanted to
In addition to donating items for our coffee hour for after Vespers,
great Vespers when everybody from the metropolis comes and joins us for our patronal feast,
we're also on Thursday evening at 5.30.
We're going to be setting up the upper hall.
So I'm especially talking to Philoptocos members, but anybody can come and help.
If you could come and help set up the hall.
It shouldn't take that long, hour, hour and a half.
depending on how many people we have.
And then on Friday, we're going to start cutting fruit and everything,
the mad rush that is before the Vesper service, starting at 3.
So if you can come, we'll be putting together plates of cookies and fruits
and hummus and pita and all of that to go out on the tables for the reception.
So if you could come on either Thursday or on Friday at 3,
that would be your help would be most appreciated. And then of course, clean up afterwards. It'll be
a long, will have been a long day for most of us. And so many hands make light work as the saying
goes. So if you have any questions, come and talk to me. If you know what you're baking or bringing
food wise, it would be very helpful. If you don't know how to sign up on the sign up genius,
if you come and talk to me.
But the Sign Up Genius...
has the list of everything that we need.
So if you're wondering what to bring,
that's where you should look.
All right.
Thank you, Father.
So if you heard that, great.
If you haven't heard it,
the poster is up here,
and I hope there's a few more upstairs for us
just so that you can read through it.
In the bulletin,
there's also the week services.
Tomorrow night being Monday night,
we have Paraclisi next door in the chapel
at 7 o'clock.
Wednesday evening,
we have Paraclisi next door in the chapel
at 7 o'clock.
o'clock. Friday, we have great vespers here for the feast of the Dormition of the Theotokos.
And Saturday morning, we have liturgy for the feast of our parish here. We will be, as of now,
we're being joined by His Eminence Metropolitan Methodio Saturday morning for Earth, Rosen Liturgy.
And we have the August calendar up and about. Now, I'm not so sure what has happened in the past,
but at this point we're going to do it now
Um, Richard, here's a curveball because I forgot to remind you this morning, but as long as you stick with the Lord, have mercies. We're good. We're going to do a 40 day baby blessing for one of our very own. We're going to welcome them into the church. It's best done. I'm sorry, you can stay close, but it's best done with people in the church because it's called the churching, right? We're welcoming the mother back for the first time after having given birth. And we're introducing the newest member of the parish to the rest of the community.
So welcome you three.
here we go. Can we get to the beginning here? You guys doing okay? Good timing. That's good timing.
Blessed is our God now and forever and to the ages of ages. Glory to the Father and to the Son and to
the Holy Spirit now and forever to the ages of ages. Amen. Through the prayers of the Theotokos
and of all the saints, grant us, Lord, your peace and have mercy on us as the only merciful one.
Let us pray to the Lord. Lord have mercy. Lord God Almighty, the Father.
of our Lord Jesus Christ, by your word you have made all creatures both rational and unreasoning.
You have brought all things into being out of nothingness. To you we pray and we beseech
receive this your handmaid Jamie Dimitra, whom it was your will to preserve in childbirth that she
comes now into your holy church so that she may be found worthy to receive without judgment your
sacred mysteries. And bless this child which she has born. Increase him and sanctify him. Give him
understanding and a prudent and virtuous mind. For it is you who have brought him forth into the light
so that he may be found worthy in due time.
of the spiritual light and must be numbered among your blessed flock through your only begotten son
with whom you are blessed together with your all holy good and life-giving spirit now and forever
to the ages of ages amen peace be with all of you and with your spirit let us bow our heads to the
lord lord our god through the incarnation of your only begotten son you came to save humankind come
also to this your handmade dimitra and through the prayers of the honorable priesthood counter
worthy to find shelter in your holy catholic and apostolic church and enter into the temple of your
glory.
to partake of the precious body and blood of your Christ as she fulfills the 40 days.
Thus entering your holy dwelling place, you may join us in glorifying your holy name of
the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit, now and forevermore.
Amen.
Let us pray to the Lord.
Lord God, on the 40th day, you were brought as an infant to the temple of the law by Mary,
your ever virgin and holy mother, and held in the arms of the righteous Simeon.
Will you, as sovereign Lord, also bless this infant brought here to be presented to you,
the author of all.
will you bless them
and advance him in every good work pleasing to you.
And by the signing with the mark of your cross,
will you put to flight every opposing force.
For you keep watch over infants, Lord,
so that when he is made worthy of holy baptism,
he may gain the portion of the elect of your kingdom,
safeguarded with us by the grace of the holy,
consubstantial, and undivided Trinity.
For to you are due, all glory and thanksgiving,
and worship us to your Father, who is from everlasting,
your all-holy good and life-creating spirit,
now and forevermore.
Peace be with all of you.
And with your spirit.
God.
Father, the omnipotent one, through the great prophet Isaiah, you foretold to us that your
only begotten son would take flesh from a virgin, and in latter days, in your good pleasure
and in harmony with the Holy Spirit, in your boundless love, you condescended to be born
of her for the salvation of us mortals.
And in keeping with the custom of your holy temple, when the days of purification had
been fulfilled, as a true lawgiver, you endured, being brought into the sanctuary and deigned
to be held in the arms of the righteous Simeon, as the one who watches over infants, Lord,
bless this child and also its parents and its sponsors.
to be, and in due time render him
worthy of rebirth in water and the Spirit.
Number him among your holy flock of
rational sheep who invoke the name of your Christ.
For though you dwell on high, you look upon
the lowly, and we offer glory to you, Father, Son,
and Holy Spirit, now and forever to the
ages of ages. Amen. So, if
you can, Ryan, put his bottom right here. Put
his head right in my elbow. Nice and
easy. Gently. Perfect.
And you two slowly follow
me right up this middle aisle, okay?
The servant
of God's healing,
Thank you.
in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit.
The servant of God, Thee, is churched in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit.
In the midst of the congregation, I will praise you.
Amen.
Servant of God, the O's church, in the name of the Father, and of the Son, and of the Holy Spirit.
You guys can wait right here. I'll be right back.
You ready, buddy?
Lord, now let your servant depart in peace according to your word.
For my eyes have seen your salvation, which you have prepared in the presence of all peoples.
A light to enlighten Gentiles, and glory for Israel, your people.
Glory to you.
O God, I give glory to you.
May he who condescended to be held in the arms of the righteous Simeon for our salvation, Christ our true God,
through the prayers of his pure and spotless Holy Mother, through the power of the precious and life-giving cross,
the protection of the honorable
body, this powers of heaven, the prayers of the glorious
prophet and foreigner, John the Baptist,
of the holy, glorious, and praiseworthy apostles, the holy,
glorious, victorious martyrs of our venerable and God-bearing
fathers, the holy, righteous ancestors
of God, Yoachim and Anna,
and of the dormition of the Virgin Mary and of all
the saints, have mercy upon us and save us as our good
and loving and merciful God.
Through the prayers of our holy fathers, Lord
Jesus Christ, our God, have mercy
upon us and save us.
Amen.
It's like you really woke up just now.
Congratulations.
you two here's your newest member yes yes I'm gonna give you right back to
Bob okay I'm gonna give you right back to Ryan here you go daddy now Jamie
would you like to receive communion why don't you sit tight now this you'll
forgive me for because it's a little out of sequence but it's because I didn't
see them in the narthex
before communion and I felt really bad throwing our chanters for a wild goose
chase but the reason we have the 40-day baby blessing is as much for the child
to be introduced to the parish but also for the mother to receive communion for
the first time since giving birth
God bless you guys.
Okay.
I think that's everything.
Do we have anything else we haven't covered?
Want to turn around?
want to show off your little baby to everybody
everybody. Congratulations once again. I don't think I can hold you hostage anymore. Thank
you for being here with us today. Once again, congratulations. Upstairs, we have coffee
hour. Remember Monday night, we have paraklisi. Wednesday night, we have paraklisi Friday evening,
Great Vespers, and Saturday morning Orthroson Liturgy. God bless.
keep all of you may you all make it right up these stairs carefully don't forget our little basket
there on your right and once again see how did he did anybody take a picture of you guys or for
you guys his mom here somebody oh she's back let's go get her up here in a second and we'll take a
picture before everybody goes up blessings of the lord
For God, not forever, for the ages of ages of me.
You want it?
Yes, no, it doesn't look like you want it.
Blessings of the Lord.
Sourdough.
See you guys upstairs?
You're running off on me.
Blessings of the Lord.
Blessing are they who hunger and thirst after justice, for they shall be filled.
Blessed are the merciful, for they shall...
obtain mercy, our dread enemy,
used food to tempt our father Adam out of God's paradise.
But Christ our Savior used the cross to lead the way for the thief to return.
And so he cried, remember me when you come again in kingly glory, Lord.
Blessed are the pure.
your heart, for they shall see God. I now venerate your sufferings and also glorify
your resurrection. Along with Adam and the thief, with united voice, both radiant and
loud i cry to you remember me when you come again in kingly glory
Lord.
Blessed are the peacemakers,
for they shall be called
the children of God.
You were crucified,
a sinless one,
and by your own will
you were laid in the grave.
But you arose again as God
and raised Adam
with your self-lovinghood
I'll sleep now
I remember me when you come again in King Me, glory Lord.
Blessed are those who are persecuted for justice's sake,
for theirs is the kingdom of heaven.
You raised up the temple of your flesh by your entombment for three days, O Christ God.
and then you'll
raised up from the grave,
those who've fallen from Adam's line with Adam too.
As he cried, remember me
when you come again in kingly glory, Lord.
Blessed are you,
and men shall revile you and persecute you,
and shall say all manner of evil
against you falsely for my sake.
O Christ God, the women bearing her
approached your grave sight with bitter tears.
Before the break of morning light,
they found sitting there an angel.
The time of morning is past.
Thank you.
here
Who started?
So are you there?
Oh, it's over.
I heard you.
What's the three-man?